<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>steve.codes</title><link>https://www.steve.codes/</link><description>Recent content on steve.codes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 23:31:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.steve.codes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DALL-E Discord Bot</title><link>https://www.steve.codes/posts/2022-12-29-dalle-discord-bot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 23:31:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.steve.codes/posts/2022-12-29-dalle-discord-bot/</guid><description>Like most techies, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself fascinated with OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s DALL-E and ChatGPT. And like most techies, I&amp;rsquo;ve eagerly been telling my (uninterested) non-tech friends about the coming AI revolution. Sure, man. They couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered with creating an OpenAI account and providing their payment information, so I decided to bring the magic to them via a Discord bot. Specifically DALL-E, since there&amp;rsquo;s an API readily available to interact with it. The use case is simple: create a bot that responds to a /generate command with a DALL-E generated image.</description></item><item><title>Building Redis</title><link>https://www.steve.codes/posts/2022-10-02-building-redis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 22:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.steve.codes/posts/2022-10-02-building-redis/</guid><description>I have a great deal of respect for anyone who’s built something novel. Whether it’s a programming language, database, or web framework, it’s such an amazing feat. I’m five years into my career and I personally wouldn’t know where to start with any of these. I wish there was a clear roadmap that outlined &amp;ldquo;do this and you’ll be good enough to build something like Redis.&amp;rdquo; I think the roadmap is to just keep coding?</description></item><item><title>Learning Go</title><link>https://www.steve.codes/posts/2022-08-28-learning-go/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 22:18:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.steve.codes/posts/2022-08-28-learning-go/</guid><description>This post was supposed to be about building a barebones Redis prototype in Go. I’ve never written Go before, so I’m not sure why I thought diving head first into a complex project like this would be a good idea. I was making gradual progress, but the constant pausing to look up syntax was getting tiring. I decided to put the project on hold and take the time to learn Go a bit more methodically.</description></item><item><title>Blog Stack Part 1: Hugo and GitHub Pages</title><link>https://www.steve.codes/posts/2022-08-17-blog-stack-p1-hugo-and-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.steve.codes/posts/2022-08-17-blog-stack-p1-hugo-and-github-pages/</guid><description>Decisions, Decisions When I went to create this blog, I quickly hit decision paralysis. Should I use a CMS? Which one? Strapi? Ghost? Sanity? Should I write the frontend in Next.js, or keep it simple with a static site generator like Hugo or Jekyll? Is WordPress still a thing? Where should I host?
After hours of research, I finally decided on Next.js and Strapi. Over-engineered for the purpose of this blog, but I thought learning this stack would be interesting.</description></item></channel></rss>